export default  [

  /* Julien session */
  {
    "category": "Julien",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one of these Microsoft subsidiaries doesn't noticeably use Java?",
    "correct_answer": "id Software",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Minecraft",
        "Yammer",
        "LinkedIn"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Julien",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "In which language is coded JHipster?",
    "correct_answer": "JavaScript",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Java",
        "Go",
        "Bash"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Julien",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "In JavaScript, what is the result of \"0.1+0.2\"?",
    "correct_answer": "0.30000000000000004",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "0.3",
        "0",
        "NaN"
      ]
  },

  /* Chris session */
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which answer does not correctly describe the new, larger GitHub-hosted runners?",
    "correct_answer": "Java installed by default",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Available for Linux and Windows",
        "Static IP ranges available",
        "Auto-scaled runners by GitHub"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How would you define a set of recommended extensions for a Codespace?",
    "correct_answer": "Configure them in the extensions property of devcontainer.json",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Install them in the dockerfile",
        "Setup a script to install in the dotfiles",
        "Use settings sync to install the specific extensions"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which answer does not correctly describe code scanning in GitHub Advanced Security?",
    "correct_answer": "Third-party tools that output into a CSV format can be integrated with Code Scanning",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Third-party analysis tools can be run, and results imported to GitHub Code Scanning",
      "CodeQL treats code like data, so you can write queries to find patterns in code.",
      "Java is supported by GitHub's code analysis engine, CodeQL"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Github tool can detect vulnerabilities in the dependencies of your Github repository?",
    "correct_answer": "Dependabot",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Github copilot",
        "Github scanning",
        "Vulneracheck",
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Github Artifacts?",
    "correct_answer": "A way to store data produced by a workflow",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A cloud storage solution from Github",
        "A place to store source code",
        "A solution for an open issue",
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Github Actions?",
    "correct_answer": "A platform that allows you to automate CI/CD (Build, Test, Deployment), and react to other GitHub events.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A bot that helps you improve your DevOps Automation",
        "A tool that helps you take action on security issues inside your codebase.",
        "An AI pair programmer",
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Chris",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What tool can help you create a quick and consistent development environment?",
    "correct_answer": "GitHub Codespaces",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "GitHub Copilot",
        "GitHub Actions",
        "GitHub Container Registry",
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "GitHub secret scanning is available",
    "correct_answer": "on private repos with GitHub Advanced Security and public repos on github.com",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Only private repos on github.com",
        "GitHub Enterprise Server",
        "Only public repos on github.com"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Is it possible to create a GitHub Action workflow which reacts to GitHub Issue events (e.g. opened, new comment, closed)?",
    "correct_answer": "Yes",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "No",
        "Only on GitHub Enterprise Cloud",
        "Only with GitHub-hosted runners"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is InnerSource?",
    "correct_answer": "Bringing Open Source Practices to our internal development (e.g. removing silos)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "An early phase of Open Source Adoption",
        "When code is locked down to the teams that need it",
        "A program used to build an Open Source community internally (e.g. drive usage adoption in a secure way, encourage contributions, recognition for OSS work among employees, etc.)"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is an Open Source Program Office?",
    "correct_answer": "A program used to build an Open Source community internally (e.g. drive usage adoption in a secure way, encourage contributions, recognition for OSS work among employees, etc.)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "An early phase of Open Source Adoption",
        "Bringing Open Source Practices to our internal development (e.g. removing silos)",
        "When code is locked down to the teams that need it"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the device posture API used for?",
    "correct_answer": "To detect foldable devices screens angle",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "To monitor user's posture to avoid back pain",
        "To detect dropping devices to flush caches and prevent data loss",
        "To detect if front or back camera is used"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What was the first mainstream foldable multi-screen device?",
    "correct_answer": "Nintendo Game & Watch",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Surface Duo",
        "Galaxy Fold",
        "LG G8X ThinQ"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What CSS feature is used to create responsive designs?",
    "correct_answer": "Media queries",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Selectors",
        "Flex box",
        "Sass"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What can be used to reduce data access latency in a distributed app?",
    "correct_answer": "Cache",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Database",
        "Queue",
        "An Intel Pentium processor"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What's the main language used to develop the Microsoft Teams app?",
    "correct_answer": "JavaScript",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Java",
        "C#",
        "C++"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Azure Spring Apps?",
    "correct_answer": "Managed service for hosting Spring Apps",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A service to deploy only a single Spring Boot app",
        "A new Spring framework",
        "A new IaaS solution for hosting Spring Apps"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one(s) of these Azure solutions can you use to deploy Spring Boot App?",
    "correct_answer": "All the answers",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Spring Apps",
        "Azure App Service",
        "Azure Container Apps"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one(s) of these Azure solutions can you use to deploy Spring Cloud Apps?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Spring Apps",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Spring Cloud",
        "Azure Spring Framework",
        "All the answers"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one(s) of these Azure solutions can you use to deploy containers?",
    "correct_answer": "All the answers",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Container Instances",
        "Azure Kubernetes Service",
        "Azure Container Apps"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one(s) of these  App Servers is/are supported by App Service?",
    "correct_answer": "Tomcat and Jboss EAP",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Tomcat and Weblogic",
        "Weblogic and JBoss EAP",
        "WebSphere and Tomcat"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure Messaging solution supports JMS?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Service Bus",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Event Grid",
        "Azure Event Hub",
        "Azure Queue Storage"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which GitHub Action configures Java on a GitHub runner?",
    "correct_answer": "actions/setup-java",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "actions/initialise-java",
        "actions/configure-java",
        "actions/java-setup"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Github Artifacts?",
    "correct_answer": "A way to store data produced by a workflow",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A cloud storage solution from Github",
        "A place to store source code",
        "A change request to your code base"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Microsoft product helps developers starting a new project quickly and efficiently?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Dev Box",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Virtual Desktop",
        "Windows 365",
        "Visual Workshop"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which editor integrates with Azure",
    "correct_answer": "IntelliJ",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "vim",
        "nano",
        "notepad++"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is an octopus merge?",
    "correct_answer": "It takes two or more branches and merge them in a single branch",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It stages several commits and merges them at once",
        "It's a type of octopus living in the atlantic ocean",
        "It's a merge done with Git Kraken"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is a protected branch in Github?",
    "correct_answer": "A branch which you must meet certain standards to be able to commit to it",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A secured branch which only accepts perfect code",
        "A hidden branch, and only available for specific users or groups",
        "A branch used to work on security features"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Why would you create a pull request?",
    "correct_answer": "To ask colleagues/community for code review before merging",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "To pull code from a repository",
        "To ask colleagues/community for help",
        "To contact Microsoft support"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How many Azure components do you need to create an approval flow using Java?",
    "correct_answer": "1",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2",
        "3",
        "4"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What was Github copilot trained on?",
    "correct_answer": "Public GitHub repositories",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Private GitHub repositories",
        "Windows repository",
        "Stackoverflow"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What Azure service is supporting the newest Forza Horizon 5?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Kubernetes Services",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Virtual Machines",
        "Azure Container Apps",
        "Azure SQL"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does IaaS mean?",
    "correct_answer": "Infrastructure as a Service",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Interopability as a Service",
        "Integration as a Service",
        "Instances a Service"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does SaaS mean?",
    "correct_answer": "Software as a Service",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Solution as a Service",
        "Security as a Service",
        "Selling as a Service"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does PaaS mean?",
    "correct_answer": "Platform as a Service",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Programming as a Service",
        "Pentesting as a Service",
        "Preaching as a Service"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the smallest vCPU you can choose for a Spring App in Azure Spring Apps?",
    "correct_answer": "0.5",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "1",
        "2",
        "4"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Can you get started for free with Microsoft Azure?",
    "correct_answer": "Yes, everyone can with the free tier",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "No you can't",
        "Only if you are a student",
        "Yes if you are a .NET developer"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How can you start using Microsoft Azure?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Credit Card",
        "Free trial",
        "Promo code"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Who is the biggest Open Source contributor?",
    "correct_answer": "Microsoft",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Google",
        "AWS",
        "Redhat"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Behind .NET, what is the second most watched topic on Microsoft Docs?",
    "correct_answer": "Java",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Golang",
        "PHP",
        "NodeJS"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Virtual Machine scale sets?",
    "correct_answer": "A set of virtual machines that can scale to help you meet demand",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A queuing system used for requests to a virtual machine",
        "A service to scale Java Apps",
        "A set of exact same virtual machines that can scale to help you meet demand"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How can you scale Azure VM?",
    "correct_answer": "Using Virtual Machine Scale Sets",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Using availability sets",
        "Using Azure Disaster Recovery",
        "Using replica sets"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the entry cost of App Service?",
    "correct_answer": "It's free",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It's free for Linux and 4.99€/month for Windows",
        "It's free for Windows and 4.99€/month for Linux",
        "It's 4.99€/month"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which service checks vulnarabilities in Azure Container Registry?",
    "correct_answer": "Microsoft Defender for Containers",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Microsoft Security Suite",
        "Azure Cybersecurity Program",
        "Microsoft Anti-Spyware"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the App Service SLA (Service Level Agreement)?",
    "correct_answer": "99.95%",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "99.99%",
        "99.90%",
        "99%"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What was the codename for the Azure project, 15 years back?",
    "correct_answer": "Red Dog",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "MCS",
        "Copper",
        "Zune"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which of the following Java class types provides generic CRUD methods to manage JPA objects?",
    "correct_answer": "Repository",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Controller",
        "Entity",
        "Interface"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NSG?",
    "correct_answer": "Network Security Group (A way to filter traffic)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Native Security Guard (A native service to enforce security in Azure)",
        "National Security Gate (A Belgium-Microsoft Security program)",
        "National System for Geospatial-Intelligence "
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "By when will Microsoft's datacenters be 100% running on renewable energy?",
    "correct_answer": "2025",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2023",
        "2027",
        "2030"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Where will the three Availability Zones of the new Belgian Azure datacentre come?",
    "correct_answer": "We don't even know ourselves",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Zaventem",
        "Ghent",
        "Wavre"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is not a goal of the Cloud for Sustainability cloud?",
    "correct_answer": "A marketing campaign to replace plastic straws in the Microsoft cafeterias",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Build a sustaniable IT infrastructure",
        "Reduce the environmental impact of operations",
        "Create sustainable value chains"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does ABC stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Belgian Central (the new upcoming Azure region in Belgium!)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Always Be Concerned (The mindset of assuming breach by default)",
        "American Broadcasting Corporation",
        "Artificial Bee Colony algorithm (a search algorithm)"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "How can you create resources in Azure?",
    "correct_answer": "All of them and many more…",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure CLI",
        "Terraform",
        "Azure portal"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is AKS?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Kubernetes Services",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Koffie Service",
        "Azure Kontainer Service",
        "Azure Kudo Service"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Where can I deploy my Maven-packaged Spring Boot application?",
    "correct_answer": "All off above",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "App Service",
        "VM",
        "Spring Cloud"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which service allows developers to scaffold the structure of a Spring Boot application?",
    "correct_answer": "Spring Initializr",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Maven",
        "The Azure CLI",
        "Proxer"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure service is written in Java?",
    "correct_answer": "HDInsight",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Internal Control Systems",
        "Databricks",
        "All of them"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the Digital AmBEtion Plan?",
    "correct_answer": "A plan to make every Belgian enterprise on this planet a digital company",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "The new datacenter in Belgium",
        "2Education everyone to become digital015"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which managed solution can you use for caching on Azure?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Redis Cache013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Redis on AKS",
        "Logstash",
        "Memcache"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the group id of Azure SDK?",
    "correct_answer": "com.azure",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "com.microsoft.azure",
        "com.azurewebs",
        "com.microsoft"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the license of Java binaries of the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK?",
    "correct_answer": "GPLv2",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Apache 2.0",
        "MIT",
        "Commercial License"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What are the correct lyrics for 'Java Life' rap music?",
    "correct_answer": "We sweat hard in these cubicles",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "We work hard in these cubicles",
        "We code hard in these cubicles",
        "We sleep hard in these cubicles"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When Devoxx was initiated for the first time?",
    "correct_answer": "2001",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "1999",
        "2000",
        "2002"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What was the formerly name of Devoxx?",
    "correct_answer": "Javapolis",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Belgian Java User Group",
        "Javaconf",
        "BeJava"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which XBOX Game Studios' game is implemented in Java?",
    "correct_answer": "Minecraft",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Halo",
        "Forza Horizon",
        "Age of Empire"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When was the first version of PowerBI released?",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2012",
        "2014",
        "2015"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Power Pivot?",
    "correct_answer": "It extends the analytical capabilities and services of Microsoft Excel.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It helps to create complex pivot tables",
        "It's the previous name of Power BI",
        "It doesnt exists at all."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is GetData in Power BI?",
    "correct_answer": "Get Data is a simple icon on Power BI used to import data from the source.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It's a custom function to call an external API",
        "This concept doesnt exists in PowerBI",
        "GetData is a short-cut to combine 2 excels"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Business Analysis, Data Analysis, Data Science",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Business Analysis, Data Analysis, Application Development",
        "Mobile Applications, Data Analysis, Integration",
        "Data Analytics"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is 'M language'?",
    "correct_answer": "A programming language used in Power Query",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A language to write machine learning algorithms",
        "M programming language doesnt exists",
        "M language is a dialect used in the middle-east."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does DAX stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Analysis Expression",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Annotation Example",
        "Data And Excel",
        "Data Analysis Experience"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the name of the functionality that allows users to ask natural language questions and get answers in the form of a visual?",
    "correct_answer": "Q&A",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Ask Power BI",
        "Power Answer",
        "Visualize Me"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT the name of a Power BI license?",
    "correct_answer": "Power BI Basic",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Power BI Free",
        "Power BI Pro",
        "Power BI Premium per User"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT a dataset mode in the Power BI Service?",
    "correct_answer": "Real-time",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Import",
        "Composite",
        "DirectQuery"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does 'M' in 'M Language' in Power Query stands for?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Mashup Language",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Minor Language",
        "Mostly used to cleanse data Language"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one of the following is considered to be an AI visual?",
    "correct_answer": "Key Influencer Visual",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Combo Chart",
        "Azure Map",
        "Deneb"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Whay is a Premium only capability?",
    "correct_answer": "Bring Your Own Key",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "PBI Desktop Incremental Refresh",
        "8 Scheduled refreshes a day",
        "Models lower than 1 GB"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What are the Analytics Runtimes available in Azure Synapse?",
    "correct_answer": "Apache Spark, Data Explorer, SQL",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SQL, Apache Spark",
        "Apache Spark, Data Explorer",
        "SQL, Data Explorer"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT a type of filter in a Power BI Report?",
    "correct_answer": "App-level Filters",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Page-level Filters",
        "Report-level Filters",
        "Visual-level Filters"
      ]
  },

  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When was the first version of PowerBI released?",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2012",
        "2014",
        "2015"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does .pbit stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "Power BI Template",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Power BI Information Technology",
        "Power BI Technology",
        "Power BI Tool"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What CAN'T you do with Power Query?",
    "correct_answer": "If then else conditions",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Join and append data from multiple data sources",
        "Import Data from wide range of sources",
        "Shape data"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which type of chart should be avoided when communicating data?",
    "correct_answer": "Pie charts",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Bar charts",
        "Line charts",
        "Area charts"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure SQL Deployment option(s) belong to the PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) family?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure SQL Managed Instance + Azure SQL Database",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SQL Server on Azure VMs + Azure SQL Database",
        "SQL Server on Azure VMs + Azure SQL Managed Instance",
        "All the deployment options"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which technology is often referred to as the power of blockchain with the simplicity of SQL?",
    "correct_answer": "Ledger",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Studio",
        "TDE",
        "TLS"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What best describes the Azure Data Explorer service?",
    "correct_answer": "Big data analytics cloud platform optimized for high volume, interactive queries.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Big data storage data optimized for batching non-interactive queries.",
        "Big data solution for data transformations.",
        "Data science platform"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate use case for Azure Data Explorer?",
    "correct_answer": "Log and Text analytics",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "In-memory batching processing of petabytes of information.",
        "Real-time analytics",
        "Deploying machine learning models"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which aspect of an extract, transform, and load (ETL) process makes it unsuitable for Azure Data Explorer.",
    "correct_answer": "High query concurrency.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Long running tasks",
        "Large volumes of data for ingestion.",
        "Microbatching"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does Microsoft Purview do with the data it discovers from your registered sources?",
    "correct_answer": "It catalogs and classifies the data that is scanned.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It moves the data to your Azure subscription, automatically creating the necessary storage accounts.",
        "It performs data transformations to match your on-premises schemas.",
        "It makes your data publicly available"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What aspect of Microsoft Purview is used to configure the data discovery for your data sources?",
    "correct_answer": "Scan rules",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Collections",
        "Classifications",
        "Resource sets"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Data Factory component should you use to represent data that you want to ingest for processing?",
    "correct_answer": "Datasets",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Linked services",
        "Pipelines"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure data service would you use to create a graph database?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Cosmos DB",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Blob",
        "Azure Table",
        "Azure Factory"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the range of nodes that a dedicated pool in Synapse have?",
    "correct_answer": "1 to 60",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "1 to 100",
        "1 to 40",
        "1 to 80"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which data redundancy in Azure would you use if you want your data to be repliacated across regions?",
    "correct_answer": "GRS (Geo-redundant)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "LRS (Locally redundant)",
        "ZRS (Zone redunandant)",
        "CRS (Country redundant)"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which distribution type is recommended when working on a dimension table in a dedicated pool?",
    "correct_answer": "Replicated",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Hash",
        "Robin",
        "Tresor"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which SAP connector in Azure leverages the SAP CDC (Change data capture) capability?",
    "correct_answer": "SAP ODP connector",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SAP HANA connector",
        "SAP BW connector",
        "SAP BTP connector"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the unique value Prop Microsoft can bring in a SQL migration scenario?",
    "correct_answer": "Leveraging License investments from on-prem into Azure SQL PaaS services",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "License mobility",
        "Free Assessment tooling for Discovery & Planning",
        "Assessment tooling for application profiling"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which feature is not present in Azure Cognitive Services for Language?",
    "correct_answer": "Content Generation",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "(Custom) Named Entity Recognition",
        "(Custom) Text Classification",
        "PII Detection"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which role aside from Insights Reader allows you to view Data Estate Insights when given access on a root level?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Curator",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Reader",
        "Data Source Admin",
        "Account Creator"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of Integration Runtime in Azure Data Factory?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure-Synapse Integration Runtime",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Integration Runtime",
        "Self-Hosted Integration Runtime",
        "Azure-SSIS Integration Runtime"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which languages are supported in Azure Synapse Analytics Spark Notebooks?",
    "correct_answer": "Python, Scala, SQL, C#",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Python, R, Scala, SQL",
        "Python, R, SQL, C#",
        "Python, R, Scala, C#"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "The Delta Lake framework provides ACID guarantees. What does ACID stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, and durability",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "atomicity, credibility, isolation, and durability",
        "atomicity, consistency, integration, and durability",
        "atomicity, credibility, integration, and durability"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which data processing technique is optimized to manage large volumes of data?",
    "correct_answer": "Extract, Load, Transform (ELT)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Extract, Transform, Load (ETL)",
        "Stream processing",
        "ETL & Stream processing"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one of the following visuals displays major contributors to a selected result or value?",
    "correct_answer": "Key influencers",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Matrix Chart",
        "Column and bar chart",
        "Scatter plot"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure data services support Apache Spark clusters? ",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Databricks",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Cosmos DB",
        "Azure Data Factory",
        "All of them"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which component of an Azure Data Factory can be triggered to run data ingestion tasks?",
    "correct_answer": "Pipelines",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Datasets",
        "Linked service",
        "None of the above"
      ]
  }
]